[Music]
Welcome to busy central launch event
2025 release day one. Now I will show
you new completely new functionality in
sustainability as we decide to extend
functionality inside the uh
sustainability features with automation
of scope 3 or let's call this value
chain.
uh this uh feature will be covered with
a few different sessions uh in this busy
center lunch event. So I will start with
value chain in transfer
orders. Okay, what is about if you look
what we had previously related to
sustainability we could use
sustainability journal from this wave
general journal as well or from previous
wave purchase invoice or create memo to
enter all this information is into
sustainability reg entry. So we can use
emissions for reporting all scopes about
environmental impact. So this is for
official reporting CSRD and other rules.
But now with new feature we added
additional scope. So now we have
sustainability value entries. So this is
something new and we want to track the
same way is we are tracking uh costs
with value entries. Now we have
sustainability value entry. What we have
there? We have inbound emissions in this
moment only from items. So in this
moment we do not support item charge.
This is something what will come next
wave. So this is the completed
functionality value chain is in this
moment public review. So we need to
extend few more things next wave but so
you can track uh your emissions related
to one specific item with your purchase
documents. Then additional you can have
additional impact on these values these
sustainability values from transfer
order assembly order production order.
So you can produce you can calculate new
values for your new finished goods for
example and once when you have all these
impact with all these changes with um
emissions total emissions all of them
will be showed in a sales invoice. In
this moment we do not have print print
out for sales invoice but you can find
this information on your sales invoice
or posted sales invoice without any
problem. So this is something what you
will
get. Okay let's see how it works with
transfer
orders first what I want to emphasize it
works with carbon equivalent only. So
system will calculate whatever you enter
all three gas emissions system will
automatically calculate to carbon
equivalent and all these future tracking
with sustainability value entry will be
related to carbon equivalent only the
idea is to use transfer orders as our
internal transport
emissions maybe some other reasons but
this is our primary reason because in
general business center doesn't have
transportation module but there's often
a case that we have some internal
transport because one location is one
city, another location, another city. So
we have internal transfer from location
to location. So you can use transfer
order to add additional emission for
specific item or items in transfer order
and when you post you can get uh all
these details and it will increase total
item emission. or emission per item. The
same way as we are working with
um uh cost with the accounts but this is
not related with the transfer orders but
you can use some other examples. What is
important when you post you will not get
uh emissions information in both of
posted documents in posted transfer uh
shipment receipt. So it will be on in
transfer
shipment. Okay. when you post you will
get sustainability value entry as I said
with all these details very very similar
as we had value entries so we didn't try
to rein the wheel so this is the same
approach as we're using for costing what
is different in this model not only this
but uh in this in this moment in this
way we are limited only on average
method in the future we will see on your
on your feedback if you if you want to
extend to different method but in this
moment this is average method only.
Okay, let's look how you can enable.
First, you need to start with
sustainability setup. You need to go to
procar procurement fast tab and then you
will find enable value chain tracking
field. When you enable this value chain
tracking field, you will get warning
message. Why warning message? Because
again this is in public preview. So our
suggestion will be first try it test it
in your sandbox environment.
We tested it works but our suggestion
will be because maybe you will miss some
of functionality what will come in next
wave. So please first try in your
sandbox. But what is about enablement?
Without enable this functionality you
will not see uh these fields neither in
trans transport transfer orders or some
other options. But in this case in
transfer orders you will have BDC as
usual. No difference in user experience.
But when you enable you will see new
field in your transfer order. Okay,
let's look for the beginning as we are
starting with one item card. We just
created item card and we didn't had any
purchase in before that. So when you see
for the first time all default CO2 and
metal and other emissions are empty and
you want to start tracking because maybe
you have something already in stock
before you decided to start uh with this
functionality. So what you can do you
can enter manually all three gas
emissions default and then you can just
click calculate CO2E and system will
calculate so you can proceed with your
further documents. But when you the
moment when you post your purchase
document system will automatically
update these values with what came from
your purchase posted purchase invoice.
So let's switch to purchase document and
you can see I have one purchase invoice
with two items and then you can find
emission CO2 emission uh for methan for
latium. So you have this is not
something new this is as we had pre
previously but what do I want to mention
uh when you enable this uh value chain
tracking in this moment when you when
you have enabled system will post both
sustainability entry and sustainability
value entry. If you didn't enable and
you still have emissions here on this
document, system will post only
sustainability ledger entry. So system
will not treat sustainability value
entry at all if you didn't enable this
in sustainability setup. So now I can
post the document and when I post
document I can find in um find entries
both of sustainability entries,
sustainability ledger entry and new
sustainability value entry. When I open
sustainability value entry, I will find
all these details I mentioned. You will
see uh sustainability value quantity,
what is CO2 equivalent per unit. So all
these details very very similar again as
I mentioned with standard value entry.
This is the most important part. So you
have uh document type, you have item
number, all these details, document
number, values related to uh car equal
and so okay let's move back to this item
I already show. Now when you look we
have updated emissions. So even we
didn't run we do not need to run
calculate CO2. So calculate CO2E action
is only if you have empty values here
and you want to enter manually and then
to run to get carbon equivalent final uh
information. But if you're using
purchase document system will
automatically fill in all these three uh
emissions and plus CO2 E per unit
already calculated based on these values
and emission
fees. Okay, let's now switch to transfer
order. When you open transfer order
again as I said everything is business
as usual except this one new field and
again if you didn't enable a track value
chain this field not be visible but now
as I enable you can find total uh carbon
equivalent and what you can do you can
enter total emissions related to this
transfer. So in this case I had total
emission of 700 kg of carbon equivalent
and I split this to these two lines. So
in this case there is no an option to
put something in a header. So to
recalculate you need to enter in both of
lines what is their piece of carbon
emissions. So when you enter here and
post the
documents everything will finish
everything posted and when you open post
the transfer shipment and go to find
entries again you can find
sustainability value entries. What you
can see here there is no sustainability
ledger entry because sustainability
ledger entry is related only with
incoming emissions not internal. So we
have only sustainability value entry.
When we open sustainability when you
entry you can see these two new lines
and in both of lines you will see CO2 E
per unit. What is specific here? Other
values related to items are negative
because this is shipment but as related
to shipment we have increasing. So uh
quantity is decreasing in a shipment but
with shipment emission is increasing. So
this is in a plus this is positive
value. So you have per unit why per unit
because we had 100 previously for first
line but we had 10 pieces in the second
line we had 600 but 60 pieces. So for
both of them system calculated as uh it
was related to total emissions but
system calculated what is carbon
equivalent per unit. So this is the most
important part in sustainability value
entry. And then when you move back to
item card, you will see that we had now
new value in uh carbon equivalent per
unit because previously it was uh 111
now we had 121 because we had additional
10 kilograms per this unit of emissions.
So this is part related uh to value
chain and transfer orders. Again this is
just one piece of value chain
functionality. So please watch another
sessions also some bit and other
sessions but especially these ones
related to value chain to get completely
picture about that. So thank you for
watching this video.